

## **Projects**

## PyStrava - Fitness App | <u>GitHub</u> | Dashboard

 Tools: Python, APIs, Google Looker, Machine Learning

### Bike Sharing Business Analysis | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Dashboard</u>

• Tools: Jupyter, Tableau

# Austin Coffee Shop Map | GitHub | Dashboard

• Jupyter, Tableau, APIs

#### Song Recommendation App | Github

• Tools: Python, Jupyter, SQL, Flask, HTML, Bootstrap, Heroku

## **Education**

**B.S. Economics**Anahuac University | Mexico City

**Certificate, Data Analytics**University of Texas | Austin, TX

### Contact

Phone: 737.333.4559

LinkedIn: Manuel Elizaldi

Email: manuelelizaldib@gmail.com

Website

## MANUEL ELIZALDI

### BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE ANALYST

### **Summary**

Highly motivated, bilingual, results-driven student of life with 4+ years of analytical and data modeling experience. Seeking an opportunity to utilize and expand upon my acquired data analytics experience, and add positive value wherever I earn the opportunity. I live in Austin, TX, and am open to hybrid or remote positions.

## **Professional Experience**

### **Business Intelligence Analyst**

Aug. 2021 - Jan. 2023

Tethr I Austin, TX

- Helped increase user engagement by 50% by using data to improve app features.
- Helped save the company +\$100k by assisting with the training of a speech transcription engine and using Python scripts to upload the resulting data to the app.
- Collaborated daily with 2 to 4 clients to understand and translate business needs into statistical/machine learning models and reports which yielded ~\$100k in revenue.
- Helped train an Al Fraud Bot which was offered as a service to a Fortune 500 company, securing a deal of ~\$30k
- Automated the processing of millions of rows of data from Azure SQL databases to improve real-time reporting of product metrics for multiple teams.
- Developed an automation system for weekly and monthly reports on various aspects of the company and customer data.

#### **Research Assistant**

Aug. 2018 - Jun. 2020

Anahuac University I Mexico City, Mexico

- Extracted, reviewed, and cleaned data from different sources to aid in the process of building economic models
- Assessed the implementation of economic public policy with the cooperation of Mexico City's government
- Co-authored economic articles concerning Public Policy, Macroeconomics, and Global Finance of the United States, Mexico, and Mexico City

#### **Sales Consultant**

Aug. 2015 - Aug. 2018

Anahuac University I Mexico City, Mexico

- Established a sales strategy to expand the foreign student population by ~10%
- Advised potential students on college applications and possible finance/scholarships
- Helped to smoothly run a community of 500+ students
- Developed an Excel database with client's information that could be leveraged to achieve goals and follow up on their registration process
- Built an Excel database for potential foreign students to follow their registration process